## SUSIE BUTLER

## WEB DEVELOPER | PHOTOGRAPHER | ARTIST



### CAREER OBJECTIVE

Diligent professional with 5 years of multidisciplinary engineering experience and 4 years of web development experience aiming to successfully fill the web developer role on your team. Strong technical and artistic background with a passion for front-end development.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### OWNER, OPERATOR, AND WEB DEVELOPER

Orca Web Services, LLC / Everett, WA / 2019 - Present

- Expand the web presence of small businesses through the design and development of custom WordPress websites using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, and PHP.
- 100% on-time completion of front-end web development contract work for eLearning cybersecurity awareness courseware clients MediaPRO and KnowBe4.

#### **COURSEWARE WEB DEVELOPER**

MediaPRO / Bothell, WA / 2018 - 2019

 Improved client cybersecurity awareness programs in over 21 languages by developing web-based, eLearning courseware using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, and XML. 100% on-time completion of new content and client customization work.

#### **WEB DEVELOPER**

TERRA Staffing Group / Everett, WA / 2017 - 2018

 Reduced the amount of time that recruiters spent on administrative tasks by developing features for the company's proprietary internal web applications using HTML/CSS, jQuery/JavaScript, PHP, AJAX, SQL, and Bootstrap.

#### **SYSTEMS ENGINEER**

The Boeing Company / Everett, WA / 2015 - 2017

- Enhanced the organization's communications by developing 5 intranet websites using HTML/CSS and JavaScript in accordance with Boeing's intranet style guide.
- Streamlined the Specification Control Drawing (SCD) process to help save engineering time. Built a web application to guide engineers through the process and collect feedback for future improvement and time savings.
- Managed the completion of the team's requirement validation and verification tasks to help keep the 777X airplane program on-schedule.

#### MANUFACTURING ENGINEER

The Boeing Company / Everett, WA / 2012 - 2015

- Saved the organization engineering time by writing Excel VBA macros to complete repetitive, manual spreadsheet tasks.
- Enabled the successful completion of a flight test program in a contract with NASA by writing the Flight Configuration Control (FC) engineering definition documents detailing the installation of Active Flow Control Rudder parts onto the test aircraft.
- Enabled the continuation of 767-model airplane production by co-leading a project to design and build a large tooling stand for the factory within a tight timeframe.

(206) 227-0319

Everett, WA

https://SusieButler.com

### **EDUCATION**

# UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA-LOS ANGELES (UCLA)

Los Angeles, CA

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) Mechanical Engineering (2012)

## UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA-DAVIS Davis, CA

Certificate - Web Development (2017)

## FLORIDA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY Melbourne, FL

Graduate Certificate - Business Management (2015)

## **SKILLS AND TOOLS**

HTML/CSS

JavaScript/jQuery

PHP

SQL

MySQL

AJAX

WordPress & WooCommerce

**Bootstrap** 

Responsive Web Design

Git Workflow

Visual Studio Code

Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Lightroom, Illustrator, Premiere)

**Digital Photography** 

Ballet/Dance